{
    "questions":[
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "What is a module in Python?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "A module is a collection of functions and variables.",
          "A module is a file containing Python code that can be imported and used in another Python file.",
          "A module is a built-in function in Python.",
          "A module is a variable defined within a function."
        ],
        "answer": "A module is a file containing Python code that can be imported and used in another Python file."
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "What is a package in Python?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "A package is a collection of modules.",
          "A package is a single Python file.",
          "A package is a built-in function in Python.",
          "A package is a variable defined within a module."
        ],
        "answer": "A package is a collection of modules."
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "Which keyword is used to import a module in Python?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "import",
          "module",
          "require",
          "from"
        ],
        "answer": "import"
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "What is the correct way to import a module named 'example' in Python?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "import example",
          "import example.py",
          "from example import *",
          "require example"
        ],
        "answer": "import example"
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "What does the '__init__.py' file do in a Python package?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "It initializes the package.",
          "It contains documentation for the package.",
          "It is not necessary for a Python package.",
          "It marks the directory as a Python package."
        ],
        "answer": "It marks the directory as a Python package."
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true about relative imports in Python?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "Relative imports are not supported in Python.",
          "Relative imports are used to import modules from the Python standard library.",
          "Relative imports are used to import modules from the current package.",
          "Relative imports are used to import modules from the parent directory."
        ],
        "answer": "Relative imports are used to import modules from the current package."
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "Which function is used to find the list of directories contained in a package?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "dir()",
          "find()",
          "listdir()",
          "os.listdir()"
        ],
        "answer": "os.listdir()"
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the '__main__' module in Python?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "It is the main module of a Python package.",
          "It is the entry point of a Python program.",
          "It contains documentation for a Python package.",
          "It initializes all other modules in a Python package."
        ],
        "answer": "It is the entry point of a Python program."
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "What does the 'if __name__ == '__main__':' statement do in Python?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "It checks if the module is the main module of a Python package.",
          "It checks if the module is being imported or run directly.",
          "It initializes all other modules in a Python package.",
          "It contains the main function of a Python package."
        ],
        "answer": "It checks if the module is being imported or run directly."
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "Which statement is used to access functions or variables from a module in Python?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "import",
          "module",
          "require",
          "from"
        ],
        "answer": "from"
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "How can you create an alias for a module in Python?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "Using the 'import' statement",
          "Using the 'as' keyword",
          "Using the 'alias' keyword",
          "Using the 'module' keyword"
        ],
        "answer": "Using the 'as' keyword"
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the '__all__' variable in Python?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "It contains a list of all modules in a package.",
          "It contains a list of all functions and variables that should be imported when using 'from module import *'.",
          "It contains a list of built-in functions in Python.",
          "It is not used in Python."
        ],
        "answer": "It contains a list of all functions and variables that should be imported when using 'from module import *'."
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the '__init__.py' file in a Python package?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "It contains documentation for the package.",
          "It initializes the package.",
          "It is not necessary for a Python package.",
          "It marks the directory as a Python package."
        ],
        "answer": "It marks the directory as a Python package."
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the 'setup.py' file in a Python package?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "It initializes the package.",
          "It contains documentation for the package.",
          "It is used to install the package using pip.",
          "It is not necessary for a Python package."
        ],
        "answer": "It is used to install the package using pip."
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the '__file__' attribute in Python modules?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "It contains the source code of the module.",
          "It contains the name of the module.",
          "It contains the path to the module's source file.",
          "It is not used in Python."
        ],
        "answer": "It contains the path to the module's source file."
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true about Python packages?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "A Python package can contain only one module.",
          "A Python package cannot contain other packages.",
          "A Python package must have a '__init__.py' file to be recognized as a package.",
          "A Python package cannot be nested within another package."
        ],
        "answer": "A Python package must have a '__init__.py' file to be recognized as a package."
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "Which function is used to find the path of a module in Python?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "os.path()",
          "path()",
          "module_path()",
          "os.path.dirname()"
        ],
        "answer": "os.path.dirname()"
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
      "languageId": 2,
      "topicId": 38,
      "questions": {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the 'site-packages' directory in Python?",
        "code": "",
        "option": [
          "It contains the standard library modules.",
          "It contains third-party modules installed using pip.",
          "It is used to store temporary files.",
          "It is not used in Python."
        ],
        "answer": "It contains third-party modules installed using pip."
      },
      "level": "beginner",
      "mark": 1,
      "time": 1
    },
    {
        "languageId": 2,
        "topicId": 38,
        "questions": {
          "question": "What is the purpose of the 'sys.path' list in Python?",
          "code": "",
          "option": [
            "It contains the paths to the standard library modules.",
            "It contains the paths to the Python interpreter.",
            "It contains the paths to the user-defined modules and packages.",
            "It is not used in Python."
          ],
          "answer": "It contains the paths to the user-defined modules and packages."
        },
        "level": "beginner",
        "mark": 1,
        "time": 1
      },
      {
        "languageId": 2,
        "topicId": 38,
        "questions": {
          "question": "Which statement is used to remove a module or package from memory in Python?",
          "code": "",
          "option": [
            "remove",
            "unload",
            "del",
            "remove_module"
          ],
          "answer": "del"
        },
        "level": "beginner",
        "mark": 1,
        "time": 1
      }
  ]
}  